[{"answer": "Yes, give or take a little.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 28, "question": "That's what you believe, isn't it, fundamentally?", "qSentId": 27}, {"answer": "Oh, I -- but I -- I do accept that, with -- with respect to those vague terms in the Constitution such as equal protection of the laws, due process of law, cruel and unusual punishments.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 34, "question": "Why are you not prepared to accept that that means you can move with the times, to evolve it?", "qSentId": 33}, {"answer": "I -- I'm not pro.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 48, "question": "How do you equate that, as man of fairness and justice, how do you continue to be so pro something which is so obviously flawed?", "qSentId": 47}, {"answer": "No, I don't think it becomes a punishment.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 75, "question": "That -- that becomes a punishment, doesn't it?", "qSentId": 74}, {"answer": "I'm not for it.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 81, "question": "But what about if you're an innocent person being waterboarded?", "qSentId": 80}, {"answer": "Well, that's lovely.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 92, "question": "-- isn't it down to the Supreme Court to effectively give a -- a more modern interpretation of the spirit of what that means, to adapt it to modern times?", "qSentId": 91}, {"answer": "Well, I don't think it is, because, look, the -- the background principle of all of this is democracy.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 96, "question": "But why don't you think it is?", "qSentId": 95}, {"answer": "I said if you're going to be serious about textualism, if the statute does not make an exception, it does not make an exception.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 115, "question": "What did you say in response to that?", "qSentId": 114}, {"answer": "Yes, if I were king, I -- I would not allow people to go about burning the American flag.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 125, "question": "And yet you personally, if you had the chance, would send them all in jail?", "qSentId": 124}, {"answer": "Well, don't forget this person has to be convicted by a jury of 12 people who unanimously have to find that he was inciting to riot.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 138, "question": "-- an -- an opinion, don't you?", "qSentId": 137}, {"answer": "Well, it really means a narrow reading, a crabbed reading of statutory words or of constitutional words.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 148, "question": "What does that mean?", "qSentId": 147}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 158, "question": "And I -- I do think it's been abused, don't you?", "qSentId": 157}, {"answer": "It's -- it's -- it's utterly impossible.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 167, "question": "Can't you?", "qSentId": 166}, {"answer": "Yes, but newspaper publishers aren't buying elections.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 172, "question": "Would they not say this is abridging my speech?", "qSentId": 171}, {"answer": "Newspapers endorse political candidates all the time.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 178, "question": "And it shouldn't be susceptible to the highest bidder, should it?", "qSentId": 177}, {"answer": "Do you think the...", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 184, "question": "And are you going to limit the amount of money they can spend on it?", "qSentId": 183}, {"answer": "Oh, I certainly think not.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 187, "question": "Do you think, perhaps, they should be?", "qSentId": 186}, {"answer": "Oh, of course.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 193, "question": "Is there any limit, in your eyes, to freedom of speech?", "qSentId": 192}, {"answer": "I'm a textualist.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 195, "question": "Is -- is there -- what are the limitations in -- to you?", "qSentId": 194}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 204, "question": "Isn't that a form of insurrection?", "qSentId": 203}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 207, "question": "Isn't it?", "qSentId": 206}, {"answer": "One of the more complex things about you, just -- which I -- I think is -- has been admired and criticized in equal measure, the case I would put to you, where I think it's interesting where you dissented against something where I think common sense would have dictated the opposite, was \"Maryland v. Craig,\" a young girl who had been abused by a child molester.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 218, "question": "What about that?", "qSentId": 217}, {"answer": "CALIA: What it says it what it says.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 239, "question": "-- abused and is actually traumatized by what happened?", "qSentId": 238}, {"answer": "No, I -- I sleep very well at night knowing that I'm doing what I suppose -- what I am supposed to do, which is to apply -- to apply the Constitution.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 241, "question": "Do you go home at night, when you dissent in that particular case, do you have misgivings about it, person -- on a personal level, or are you always able to divorce that from your, as you would say, legal responsibility to uphold the letter of the Constitution?", "qSentId": 240}, {"answer": "I -- I wouldn't say violently.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 256, "question": "Why were you so violently opposed to it?", "qSentId": 255}, {"answer": "Of -- of course.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 279, "question": "Did they?", "qSentId": 278}, {"answer": "What -- I -- I don't know why.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 286, "question": "It wouldn't have even entered their minds, would it?", "qSentId": 285}, {"answer": "Because at the time, it was...", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 288, "question": "Why wouldn't it?", "qSentId": 287}, {"answer": "They did, but it was not an issue that they would ever consider framing in the Constitution.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 290, "question": "They -- they didn't have wives and daughters that they cared about?", "qSentId": 289}, {"answer": "My view is regardless of whether you think prohibiting abortion is good or whether you think prohibiting abortion is bad, regardless of how you come out on that, my only point is the Constitution does not say anything about it.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 294, "question": "I mean, why would you be instinctively against that?", "qSentId": 293}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 315, "question": "My hardest?", "qSentId": 314}, {"answer": "No, I don't.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 325, "question": "You want me to describe it really?", "qSentId": 324}, {"answer": "Look it, I -- my court didn't -- didn't bring the case into the court.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 339, "question": "Justice Scalia?", "qSentId": 338}, {"answer": "Oh, no regrets at all, especially since it's clear that the thing would have ended up the same way anyway.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 346, "question": "No regrets?", "qSentId": 345}, {"answer": "Oh, that's not so unusual.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 364, "question": "I mean, is it just me that thinks it's a bit weird that a guy can join the Supreme Court and literally not ask any questions?", "qSentId": 363}, {"answer": "There -- there are clashes on -- on legal questions, but not personally.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 393, "question": "Are there clashes there?", "qSentId": 392}, {"answer": "I think I read it in some of the papers.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 401, "question": "Who told you that?", "qSentId": 400}, {"answer": "I'm not going to talk about -- no, I haven't had a falling out with Justice Roberts.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 406, "question": "So you've had no falling out with Justice Roberts?", "qSentId": 405}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 408, "question": "Loud words exchanged?", "qSentId": 407}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 410, "question": "Slamming of doors?", "qSentId": 409}, {"answer": "Nothing like that.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 412, "question": "Nothing like that?", "qSentId": 411}, {"answer": "My best buddy on the court is Ruth Bader Ginsburg, has always been.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 414, "question": "Best buddies?", "qSentId": 413}, {"answer": "I like to play tennis.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 420, "question": "What do you like to do when you're not presiding in the Supreme Court?", "qSentId": 419}, {"answer": "I have, indeed.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 424, "question": "You've been hunting with Dick Cheney, haven't you?", "qSentId": 423}, {"answer": "Well, in that case, I had accepted the invitation long before the case that was the alleged source of the conflict was before the court.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 435, "question": "How -- how carefully do you think, before you accept an invitation to go hunting with Dick Cheney, how hard do you think about that as a potential conflict?", "qSentId": 434}, {"answer": "No, I -- I usually don't read it.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 447, "question": "Does that annoy you?", "qSentId": 446}, {"answer": "Look it, I have ruled against the government when Republicans were in the administration and I've ruled for the government when Democrats were in the admin -- I couldn't care less who the president is or what the administration is.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 456, "question": "A good judge will decide cases based on a governing text that go against what the judge might think is wise policy, isn't that true?", "qSentId": 455}, {"answer": "Not a single one of them.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 460, "question": "-- from a politically motivated manner?", "qSentId": 459}, {"answer": "It -- it offends me that -- that -- that people point to the fact -- and they didn't used to be able to when -- when -- when David Souter and John Paul Stevens were still on the court.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 479, "question": "-- does it offend you that his integrity would be questioned like that?", "qSentId": 478}, {"answer": "I'd say so, yes.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 499, "question": "And you're married a very long time to a long-suffering woman, would you say?", "qSentId": 498}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 506, "question": "Have I ever broken the law?", "qSentId": 505}, {"answer": "Oh, yes.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 509, "question": "Have you ever been caught?", "qSentId": 508}, {"answer": "-- I am pretty much a law-abiding sort.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 519, "question": "-- in your life?", "qSentId": 518}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 526, "question": "My guilty pleasure?", "qSentId": 525}, {"answer": "I've got lots of guilty pleasures.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 529, "question": "How can -- how can it be pleasurable if it's guilty?", "qSentId": 528}, {"answer": "Fifty-two years.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 538, "question": "Now, you've been married for how long?", "qSentId": 537}, {"answer": "Thirty-three.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 543, "question": "How many grandchildren are there?", "qSentId": 542}, {"answer": "Maureen made it very clear early on that if we split up, I would get the children.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 546, "question": "What has been the secret of -- of such a longstanding marriage, do you think?", "qSentId": 545}, {"answer": "She has -- she has worked very hard.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 550, "question": "Did you mean that?", "qSentId": 549}, {"answer": "Hmmm.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 559, "question": "Prop -- properly in love?", "qSentId": 558}, {"answer": "Of course I'll retire.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 564, "question": "Will you ever retire?", "qSentId": 563}, {"answer": "Wow!", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 568, "question": "And as -- as we sit here now, what would you say your greatest achievement has been as a Supreme Court justice?", "qSentId": 567}, {"answer": "The framing of the Constitution.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 581, "question": "What is?", "qSentId": 580}, {"answer": "No I -- I don't -- I don't use the -- Madison's notes as authoritative on the meaning of the Constitution.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 585, "question": "What's the difference, really?", "qSentId": 584}, {"answer": "You have to read the Federalist Papers to answer that question.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 594, "question": "Why are you so convinced that these guys, over 200 years ago, were so right?", "qSentId": 593}, {"answer": "I wish we had a few of them now.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 604, "question": "Do you wish we had a few of them now?", "qSentId": 603}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 636, "question": "Do you still get a little thrill when you come in?", "qSentId": 635}, {"answer": "No, no, no --", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 641, "question": "Most in history?", "qSentId": 640}, {"answer": "In your lifetime, yeah.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 643, "question": "In my lifetime?", "qSentId": 642}, {"answer": "He had a way of -- he was the great communicator.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 647, "question": "What made him special?", "qSentId": 646}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 650, "question": "Did he give you any advice when he put you forward?", "qSentId": 649}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 654, "question": "Did he say anything?", "qSentId": 653}, {"answer": "He almost got my name right.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 656, "question": "Would you tell me if he had?", "qSentId": 655}, {"answer": "I have a lot of Italian friends.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 664, "question": "Do you ever have to pay for spaghetti bolognese in New York?", "qSentId": 663}, {"answer": "Pasta con sarde (ph) I think is the name of it.", "docId": "120718pmt", "aSentId": 674, "question": "What do you call it?", "qSentId": 673}]